<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>centiskor.ch</title><description>A Pokémon fan site dedicated to Centiskorch, a dual-type Fire/Bug Pokémon from the Galar region.</description><link>https://centiskor.ch/</link><item><title>12 facts I didn&apos;t know about Pokémon</title><link>https://centiskor.ch/blog/12-facts-i-didnt-know-about-pokemon/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://centiskor.ch/blog/12-facts-i-didnt-know-about-pokemon/</guid><description>Well, I didn&apos;t know at these facts when I first wrote this.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;(The original date I published this on my personal site was 28 Sep 2017.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Satoshi Tajiri pitched Pokémon to Nintendo but it was initially rejected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to issues with copyright, the name “CapuMon” was considered before settling on Pocket Monsters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game Freak struggled with the development of Red &amp;amp; Green in Japan. Low finances caused many of the staff to leave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tajiri worked long hours, many of them unpaid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The games were originally scheduled for a December 21, 1995 release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The American staff who localized the games tried to change the Pokémon designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Canadian French manual for Pokémon Blue, Pokémon is misspelled as “Pokémons”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/736x/a6/de/02/a6de026685b1cd9e6b15f786b24108ee--retro-games-nintendo-pokemon.jpg&quot;&gt;special Pikachu Yellow model of the Game Boy Printer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A title similar to Crystal called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pocket-monster-x-on-the-game-boy/1100-2447345/&quot;&gt;Pocket Monsters X&lt;/a&gt; (unrelated to the 2013 release) was set for an April 2000 release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Japanese version of Crystal has an emblem of Suicune’s crest on the back of the cart’s circuit board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was also developed using Pokémon Gold as its basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A promotional coin featuring Groudon and Kyogre was available with American pre-orders of Ruby and Sapphire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>33+ minutes of chill Pokémon beats</title><link>https://centiskor.ch/blog/33-minutes-of-chill-pokemon-beats/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://centiskor.ch/blog/33-minutes-of-chill-pokemon-beats/</guid><description>Pocket Monster Vibes is the perfect background soundtrack for whatever you’re doing.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;figure class=&quot;img-center&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7pHPSmkke7M&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/images/pokemon-monster-vibes.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;480px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot; alt=&quot;an illustration of a game boy and game boy cartridge with the title Pocket Monster Vibes at the top&quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;figcaption&amp;gt;Click the image and it&apos;ll take you to the YouTube video.&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(originally written on 29th August 2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/HoopsandHipHop&quot;&gt;HoopsandHipHop&lt;/a&gt; started his YouTube channel making beats and remixes before moving towards more Pokémon-oriented videos. But those two things aren’t mutually exclusive and the above album demonstrates his creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pocket Monster Vibes&lt;/em&gt; is the perfect background soundtrack for whatever you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Awesome Pokémon illustrations by Julesdrawz</title><link>https://centiskor.ch/blog/julesdrawz-awesome-pokemon-illustrations/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://centiskor.ch/blog/julesdrawz-awesome-pokemon-illustrations/</guid><description>This illustrator knows how to capture the frenetic energy of Pokémon.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Julesdrawz is an illustrator and 2D animator with an eye for detail and stunning colours. His skills lend themselves well to the world of Pokémon where vibrancy and detail are at their peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;img-center&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/images/espeon-julesdrawz.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/images/krookodile-julesdrawz.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/images/toxtricity-julesdrawz.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/images/charizard-duraladon-julesdrawz.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&amp;gt;Images via &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/julesdrawz/&quot;&amp;gt;his Instagram&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. All rights reserved to him ©&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;He’s open for commissions so hit him up if you’re interested (I’m thinking about it myself). In the meantime, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/julesdrawz&quot;&amp;gt;follow him on Twitter&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://julesdrawz.tumblr.com/&quot;&amp;gt;Tumblr&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://ko-fi.com/julesdrawz&quot;&amp;gt;Ko-fi&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Quick thoughts on Pokémon fan demands</title><link>https://centiskor.ch/blog/quick-thoughts-pokemon-fan-demands/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://centiskor.ch/blog/quick-thoughts-pokemon-fan-demands/</guid><description>I tweeted all of this but thought I’d put it here for posterity.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;(originally written on 3rd April 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers need to understand that commercial products can’t satisfy their niche needs AND sell enough to continue production and appease shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a defender of capitalism—it’s a system we’re all part of in some way—but as part of that, we’ve seen what it can do to entities that try to please everyone and end up pleasing no one and going out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, I’ve seen a lot of Pokémon content creators start playing fan-made games on their streams and saying they wish the main games were like them. But they forget that casual gamers make up more of their market than people wanting hard mode Pokémon games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why the hell would Game Freak build in a meta-esque system by default in that case? If you wanna Nuzlocke… go Nuzlocke. If you wanna play with special rules… self-impose them. Or play the fan-made games as you already are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://lavacutcontent.com/masuda-interview-pokemon-platinum/&quot;&gt;Dr. Lava&apos;s snippets of Masuda interviews&lt;/a&gt; has made me realise he wants to make fun games for all to enjoy with expansive worlds and opportunities for people to make their own stories through them. I think that’s beautiful and it’s worked on me, clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>